Guide to the Stanford University, Libraries, Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Libraries, photographs
1967-1993
PC0058
Stanford University. Libraries.
3.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, 1994-2000
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Scope and Content
Prints, negatives, and slides documenting the libraries at Stanford University, including the Hopkins Marine Station; subjects include buildings, interiors, staff, collections, patrons, events, the Library Associates, the damage from the October 1989 earthquake, construction of the East Wing (1977-80), and the move of the Special Collections Department in 1989. Some images were prepared for the Libraries' annual reports. Individuals pictured include Ellen Poyet, David C. Weber, Cecil H. Green, Witold S. Sworakowski, and Warren Howell. There are also two photogaphs by Leo Holub of Janet Lewis, 1989.
Collection Contents
- Assorted Directors' Office, West Wing, Exterior shots of Green, 1993:; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Earthquake damage at Meyer, 1989; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Earthquake, 1989; (color negatives) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Earthquake damage Green West, including Hopkins Room, 1989; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Earthquake damage Green Library, 1989; (color prints) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Earthquake damage Green Library and staff meetings, 1989; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Earthquake damage Green Library and post-quake use of certain areas, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6b)
- Earthquake damage various libraries, 1989; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Earthquake damage in Green West, 1989; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Earthquake damage in Bender Room, 1989; (color prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Green, Cecil and directors, 1991; (B/W prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Library Associates, (color prints and negatives; 2 B/W prints) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Library Associates events, circa 1990; (B/W prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Negatives, mostly exterior of Green Library (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Negatives, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Presentation of awards, (B/W prints and negatives) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Seminar in Ida Green Room, possibly staff training, (B/W prints) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Statue in Meyer Library, (B/W prints) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Taube/Baron collection, reception at Humanities Center, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Staff picnic, Sept. 1988; (color prints and negatives) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Staff picnic, 1988; (B/W prints) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Staff picnic and staff portraits, Roll C, 1988; (B/W prints) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Staff picnic, Roll D, 1988; (B/W prints) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Staff picnic, Roll G, June 1988; (B/W prints) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Weber, David C., reception for, June 5, 1991; (color prints and negatives) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Annual Report, photos used for, 1990/91 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Annual Report, photos used for, 1991/92 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Assorted contact sheets: Green, Engineering, Music, Chemistry, Biology, Math, Physics, Art, and Branner Libraries (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Cubberley Library (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Distinguished Service Awards (91/92 year) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- General library images used for library insert in Stanford Daily, (pre 1989) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Green Library, assorted shots, (contact sheet) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Green Library dedication (with 2 other events) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Green Library exterior shots, pre October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Green Library interiors (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Green Library miscellaneous: Directors' Office staff, researchers, (negatives and contact sheet) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Gutenberg bus (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Hopkins Marine Station Library (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Howell Award to William R. Moran, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Meyer Library (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous events (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous 4x5 negatives (identified) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous prints (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Patrons and researchers (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Production items, (half-tones, screens) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Selmy, Michael (student patron?) (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Special Collections circulation desk, (color print and slide) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Special Collections, Field Reading Room, pre October 1989; (B/W print and negative) (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Staff (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Staff - Directors and others?; occasion unknown (Box 2, Folder 31)
- The Thinker sculpture (Box 2, Folder 32)
- ULC awards (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Binder of B/W negatives and contact sheets (prints from some of these negatives appear in Boxes 1 and 2), 1988-1990 (Box 3)
- Boxed slides (Box 3)
- Negatives, prints, and slides of books and manuscripts from the Department of Special Collections, some used in the Libraries Annual Reports for 1984 and 1985; includes maps, fore-edge paintings, and illustrations from books. There are also a few images of volunteers working in the Department (Box 4)
- Annual Report 1988 images: staff, David Weber and curators, page from Russell Varian's notebook (Box 5, Folder 1)
- ASUL picnics at Jasper Ridge (Leo Holub photographs; includes two of Janet Lewis), 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Howell, Antoinette (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Poyet, Ellen, circa 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Special Collections items, to illustrate Annual Reports (mostly proof sheets, no date) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Visiting Committee, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Meyer flood restoration crew, circa 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 3 millionth book publicity photos (Witold Sworakowski, Rutherford Rogers, Julius Barclay, Elmer Grieder, Warren Howell), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Technical services open house (in Meyer Library), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Special Collections party for Linda Long's departure, 1996; (negatives and contact sheets) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Slides of the construction of the east wing of S. U. Libraries, including images of the site prior to ground-breaking, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Slides from the move of Special Collections books into the tiered stacks, January 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Framed photographs of early S. U. Librarians: Dr. Woodruff, Herbert Nash, George T. Clark, C. H. Faust, Melvin Gilbert Dodge, and Nathan Van Patten (Box 7)
- Photographs from exhibits at Meyer Library on: Sculptures on campus; Underground Press (photos by Joe Riley, includes negatives),; and Libraries of Stanford, Orientation week, 1970 ca. 1980 (Box 8 os)